[
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which woman became queen and saved her people?",
    "answer": "Esther",
    "reference": "Esther 4:14"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Who was the left-handed judge who killed King Eglon?",
    "answer": "Ehud",
    "reference": "Judges 3:15-21"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "What prophet saw a vision of a valley of dry bones?",
    "answer": "Ezekiel",
    "reference": "Ezekiel 37:1-10"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Who was the prophet taken to heaven in a whirlwind?",
    "answer": "Elijah",
    "reference": "2 Kings 2:11"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Which apostle survived a snake bite on Malta?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "reference": "Acts 28:3-6"
  },
  {
    "id": 501,
    "question": "\"\"The wind bloweth where it listeth\"\" said Jesus to:",
    "answer": "Nicodemus",
    "reference": "John 3:4-8"
  },
  {
    "id": 502,
    "question": "According to 2 Timothy 3:16 all Scripture is:",
    "answer": "God-breathed and useful for his purposes",
    "reference": "2 Timothy 3:16"
  },
  {
    "id": 503,
    "question": "According to Jesus what are the most important commandments in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Love God with all your heart and love your neighbor as yourself",
    "reference": "Mark 12:29-31"
  },
  {
    "id": 504,
    "question": "According to Paul’s formulation in 1 Corinthians",
    "answer": "which is the greatest of the imperishable qualities?",
    "reference": "Love"
  },
  {
    "id": 506,
    "question": "According to the Gospel of Matthew",
    "answer": "where does Jesus give his first public sermon?",
    "reference": "On the mount"
  },
  {
    "id": 508,
    "question": "According to the NIV (New International Version) what is the shortest verse in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Job 3:2",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 514,
    "question": "As a baby how was Moses saved from Pharaoh's murderous decree?",
    "answer": "He was put in a basket and thrown into the river",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 515,
    "question": "As a shepherd David protected his flock from two dangerous animals Which ones?",
    "answer": "bear and lion",
    "reference": "1 Samuel 17:34-37"
  },
  {
    "id": 516,
    "question": "As Isaac was dying and blind",
    "answer": "who suggested that Jacob should steal the blessing?",
    "reference": "Rebekah"
  },
  {
    "id": 517,
    "question": "At what age did Jesus begin his ministry?",
    "answer": "Around 30 years old",
    "reference": "Luke 3:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 519,
    "question": "By what name is Paul of Tarsus known before he begins his missionary activity?",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 520,
    "question": "By whom were the children of Israel carried captive into Assyria?",
    "answer": "Tiglathpileser",
    "reference": "2 Kgs 15:29"
  },
  {
    "id": 522,
    "question": "Complete the verse: \"\"For God so loved the world...",
    "answer": "that he gave his one and only Son",
    "reference": "that whoever believes in him shall not perish but have eternal life.\"\""
  },
  {
    "id": 523,
    "question": "Complete this verse from Job: \"\"for the price of wisdom is …………",
    "answer": "above rubies",
    "reference": "Job 28:18"
  },
  {
    "id": 525,
    "question": "Concerning which disciple did the rumor spread that he would not die?",
    "answer": "John",
    "reference": "John 21:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 526,
    "question": "During Paul’s third missionary journey",
    "answer": "roughly for how long did he minister in the school of Tyrannus at Ephesus?",
    "reference": "2 years"
  },
  {
    "id": 530,
    "question": "Finish this verse “In every battle you will need faith as your ______ to stop the fiery arrows aimed at you by Satan”",
    "answer": "Shield",
    "reference": "Ephesians 6:16"
  },
  {
    "id": 534,
    "question": "How and where did Paul's conversion take place?",
    "answer": "He had a vision after falling to the ground near Damascus",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 535,
    "question": "How did Esau provide food for the family?",
    "answer": "He hunted",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 536,
    "question": "How did Esau respond when his birthright was taken?",
    "answer": "Threatened to kill Jacob",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 537,
    "question": "How did God appear to Moses in the book of Exodus?",
    "answer": "Through a burning bush on the mountain of God",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 539,
    "question": "How did God make them spread out across the earth?",
    "answer": "Confused their languages",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 540,
    "question": "How did Jesus reveal the one who would betray him?",
    "answer": "Dipped a piece of bread and passed it to him",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 541,
    "question": "How did Joseph interpret Pharaoh’s dream?",
    "answer": "Seven good years and seven bad years",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 543,
    "question": "How did Judas identify Jesus to the soldiers?",
    "answer": "By kissing him",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 545,
    "question": "How did Paul escape Damascus when the Jews were trying to kill him?",
    "answer": "He was let down from the city walls in a basket",
    "reference": "Acts 9:25"
  },
  {
    "id": 547,
    "question": "How does Judas notify the Roman Officials of Jesus’ identity?",
    "answer": "Judas kisses Jesus",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 548,
    "question": "How does Judas signal Jesus’s identity to the Roman officials?",
    "answer": "Kiss",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 549,
    "question": "How does the author of 1 John often refer to his readers?",
    "answer": "Children",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 550,
    "question": "How long did Jesus pray in Gethsemane?",
    "answer": "The bible does not say",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 551,
    "question": "How long did Moses’s mother hide him to escape the death edict of Pharaoh?",
    "answer": "3 months",
    "reference": "Exod 2:2"
  },
  {
    "id": 552,
    "question": "How long did the children of Israel journey in the wilderness of Shur before they found water?",
    "answer": "3 days",
    "reference": "Exod 15:22"
  },
  {
    "id": 557,
    "question": "How long were the children of Israel in Egypt?",
    "answer": "215 years",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 561,
    "question": "How many books does the Bible consist of?",
    "answer": "66 books",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 564,
    "question": "How many brothers did Joseph have?",
    "answer": "11",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 565,
    "question": "How many chapters are there in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "There are 929 chapters in the Old Testament",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 566,
    "question": "How many close disciples did Jesus have?",
    "answer": "12",
    "reference": "Luke 6:12-16"
  },
  {
    "id": 571,
    "question": "How many days did Lazarus remain in the tomb before Jesus raised him?",
    "answer": "4 days",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 572,
    "question": "How many human couples entered Noah's ark?",
    "answer": "4 couples",
    "reference": "Genesis 7:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 580,
    "question": "How many wonders did Elijah and Elisha perform altogether?",
    "answer": "24",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 582,
    "question": "How much did Judas betray Jesus for?",
    "answer": "30 silver coins",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 583,
    "question": "How old was Abraham when Isaac was born?",
    "answer": "100 years old",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 586,
    "question": "How old was Joseph when his brethren sold him into slavery?",
    "answer": "17",
    "reference": "Gen 37:2"
  },
  {
    "id": 589,
    "question": "How were the children of Israel guided in their forty years of wandering in the wilderness?",
    "answer": "By a pillar of cloud by day and a pillar of fire by night",
    "reference": "Exod 13:21"
  },
  {
    "id": 590,
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians which is the greatest of the imperishable qualities?",
    "answer": "Love",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 591,
    "question": "In the Acts of the Apostles who is Stephen?",
    "answer": "The first Christian martyr",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 592,
    "question": "In the book of Philemon who is Paul's fellow prisoner?",
    "answer": "Epaphras",
    "reference": "Philemon 1:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 593,
    "question": "In the Gospel According to John which disciple doubts Jesus’s resurrection until he sees him with his own eyes?",
    "answer": "Thomas",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 594,
    "question": "In the Gospel of Mark",
    "answer": "how does the Virgin Mary learn of her pregnancy",
    "reference": "From the angel Gabriel"
  },
  {
    "id": 600,
    "question": "In which book of the bible to we read about Haman?",
    "answer": "Esther",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 601,
    "question": "In which books of the Bible is the story of Jesus' birth told?",
    "answer": "Matthew and Luke",
    "reference": "Matthew 1 and 2; Luke 2"
  },
  {
    "id": 605,
    "question": "Jacob sent Joseph to his brothers",
    "answer": "where did he find them?",
    "reference": "Dothan"
  },
  {
    "id": 606,
    "question": "James used the example of which Old Testament figure to demonstrate how the prayers of a righteous man can have powerful results?",
    "answer": "Elijah",
    "reference": "James 5:13-18"
  },
  {
    "id": 608,
    "question": "Jesus' disciples were all:",
    "answer": "(c) Jews",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 609,
    "question": "Judas Iscariot betrayed Jesus for thirty pieces of silver What was thirty pieces of silver equivalent to in the OT?",
    "answer": "The price of a slave",
    "reference": "Exodus 21:32"
  },
  {
    "id": 612,
    "question": "Name a king who disguised themselves before going into battle and was slain by archers",
    "answer": "Ahab or Josiah",
    "reference": "1 Kings 22:34; 2 Chron 35:22"
  },
  {
    "id": 614,
    "question": "Of what wood was Noah’s Ark made?",
    "answer": "Gopher wood",
    "reference": "Gen 6:14"
  },
  {
    "id": 616,
    "question": "Paul and Silas were imprisoned during the second missionary journey",
    "answer": "but in what city did this happen?",
    "reference": "Philippi"
  },
  {
    "id": 617,
    "question": "Paul says Christians should follow whose example? (Ephesians 5)",
    "answer": "Christ’s example",
    "reference": "Ephesians 5"
  },
  {
    "id": 618,
    "question": "Paul was shipwrecked on what island?",
    "answer": "Malta",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 620,
    "question": "Prior to raising Eutychus from the dead",
    "answer": "Paul preached a lengthy sermon At what hour did he end his sermon?",
    "reference": "Midnight"
  },
  {
    "id": 621,
    "question": "The Bible is divided into",
    "answer": "2 parts: Old Testament and New Testament",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 624,
    "question": "To what city was Saul traveling when he encountered a great and blinding light?",
    "answer": "Damascus",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 625,
    "question": "Upon what mountain was Israel cursed for disobedience?",
    "answer": "Mount Ebal",
    "reference": "Deut 27:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 627,
    "question": "What \"\"ran violently down a steep place into the sea and perished in the waters\"\"?",
    "answer": "A herd of swine",
    "reference": "Matthew 8:32"
  },
  {
    "id": 630,
    "question": "What are the names of Joseph’s two sons?",
    "answer": "Ephraim and Manasseh",
    "reference": "Gen 41:51–52"
  },
  {
    "id": 631,
    "question": "What Athenian judge was converted under Paul’s preaching?",
    "answer": "Dionysius",
    "reference": "Acts 17:34"
  },
  {
    "id": 634,
    "question": "What did a woman do to Jesus in the house of Simon the leper at Bethany?",
    "answer": "Anoint him with oil",
    "reference": "Matthew 26:6-7"
  },
  {
    "id": 635,
    "question": "What did Esau receive in exchange for his birthright?",
    "answer": "Some stew",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 636,
    "question": "What did God ask Abraham to sacrifice on Mount Moriah?",
    "answer": "His only son",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 639,
    "question": "What did God tell Abraham to look at when he made him a promise?",
    "answer": "To the stars in the sky",
    "reference": "so that he could count them"
  },
  {
    "id": 641,
    "question": "What did Herod and Pilate become when Jesus stood on trial before them? Friends or Enemies?",
    "answer": "Friends",
    "reference": "Luke 23:12"
  },
  {
    "id": 642,
    "question": "What did Jacob do most of the time?",
    "answer": "Stayed in the home with his mother",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 643,
    "question": "What did Jesus do before feeding the 5",
    "answer": "000",
    "reference": "Gave thanks"
  },
  {
    "id": 647,
    "question": "What did Joshua command to stay still?",
    "answer": "Moon & Sun",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 648,
    "question": "What did Laban make Jacob do to finally marry Rachel?",
    "answer": "Work another seven years",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 650,
    "question": "What did Saul encounter when he was traveling to Damascus?",
    "answer": "A great and blinding light",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 655,
    "question": "What does Jahwe-Schammah mean?",
    "answer": "God is there",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 656,
    "question": "What does Paul call the Galatians?",
    "answer": "foolish",
    "reference": "Galatians 3:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 658,
    "question": "What does Paul say may “abound more and more in knowledge and in all judgment?”",
    "answer": "Love",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 667,
    "question": "What happened to some Galileans while they were offering sacrifices?",
    "answer": "They were slaughtered",
    "reference": "Luke 13:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 668,
    "question": "What is the central theme of the Bible?",
    "answer": "Jesus Christ",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 676,
    "question": "What is the longest chapter in the bible?",
    "answer": "Psalm 119",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 677,
    "question": "What is the longest verse in the bible?",
    "answer": "Esther 8:9",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 678,
    "question": "What is the name and age of the oldest person mentioned in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Methuselah",
    "reference": "lived 969 years"
  },
  {
    "id": 679,
    "question": "What is the name of the disciple who betrayed Jesus?",
    "answer": "Judas Iscariot",
    "reference": "Matthew 26:14-16"
  },
  {
    "id": 680,
    "question": "What is the name of the island where John wrote the book of Revelation?",
    "answer": "The island of Patmos",
    "reference": "Revelation 1:9"
  },
  {
    "id": 681,
    "question": "What is the name of the sea where Jesus calmed the storm?",
    "answer": "Sea of Galilee",
    "reference": "Mark 4:35-41"
  },
  {
    "id": 682,
    "question": "What is the name of the town where Jesus was born?",
    "answer": "Bethlehem",
    "reference": "Matthew 2:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 683,
    "question": "What is the name of the village where Christ turned water into wine?",
    "answer": "Cana of Galilee",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 684,
    "question": "What is the original meaning of the word 'Bible'?",
    "answer": "Bible is the plural of 'biblos' from the Greek and means books",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 687,
    "question": "What is the shortest book in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "2 John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 688,
    "question": "What is the shortest chapter in the bible?",
    "answer": "Psalm 117",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 689,
    "question": "What is the shortest verse in the bible?",
    "answer": "John 11:35 Jesus wept",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 691,
    "question": "What king of Judah was overtaken by an invading army and had his eyes put out?",
    "answer": "Zedekiah",
    "reference": "2 Kgs 25:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 692,
    "question": "What king was guilty of idolatry in making two golden calves and commanding the people to worship them?",
    "answer": "Jeroboam",
    "reference": "1 Kgs 12:28"
  },
  {
    "id": 693,
    "question": "What king was killed by his own sons?",
    "answer": "Sennacherib",
    "reference": "2 Kgs 19:36"
  },
  {
    "id": 695,
    "question": "What names was Moses supposed to give to the Israelites when asked about who had sent him?",
    "answer": "I am who I am",
    "reference": "Exodus 3:13-14"
  },
  {
    "id": 696,
    "question": "What occupation did Paul of Tarsus follow?",
    "answer": "Tent maker",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 697,
    "question": "What Pharisee gave a feast that Jesus attended?",
    "answer": "Simon",
    "reference": "Luke 7:36-50"
  },
  {
    "id": 700,
    "question": "What should be the 3 attitudes of Jesus' followers?",
    "answer": "Deny yourself",
    "reference": "take up your cross daily"
  },
  {
    "id": 702,
    "question": "What tribe is Paul from?",
    "answer": "Benjamin",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 705,
    "question": "What was a prophet’s usual task?",
    "answer": "To pray and to be in the service of the priests",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 708,
    "question": "What was David’s occupation before he became king?",
    "answer": "Shepherd",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 709,
    "question": "What was God’s original name for Abraham?",
    "answer": "Abram",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 714,
    "question": "What was Isaiah’s father called?",
    "answer": "Amoz",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 718,
    "question": "What was Jesus' first miracle?",
    "answer": "Turned water into wine at a wedding feast",
    "reference": "John 2:1-11"
  },
  {
    "id": 719,
    "question": "What was Joseph’s brothers’ plan to do with him?",
    "answer": "Throw him in a pit to kill him",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 720,
    "question": "What was most likely the first Gospel written?",
    "answer": "Mark",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 721,
    "question": "What was most likely the first of Paul’s letters written?",
    "answer": "1 Thessalonians",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 722,
    "question": "What was most likely the last Gospel written?",
    "answer": "John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 723,
    "question": "What was most likely the last New Testament book written?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 724,
    "question": "What was Paul’s occupation?",
    "answer": "Tentmaking",
    "reference": "Acts 18:3"
  },
  {
    "id": 725,
    "question": "What was Peter's job before he became an apostle?",
    "answer": "Fisherman",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 727,
    "question": "What was Sarah’s idea for Abram to have a child?",
    "answer": "For Abram to have a child with Hagar",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 729,
    "question": "What was Saul’s punishment for disobeying God?",
    "answer": "Kingdom torn away",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 731,
    "question": "What was Solomon famous for?",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 732,
    "question": "What was the “tabernacle” for?",
    "answer": "The tabernacle was a portable sanctuary created by Moses as a place of worship for the Hebrew tribes throughout their wandering that preceded their arrival in the Promised Land",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 733,
    "question": "What was the eighth plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Locusts",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 734,
    "question": "What was the first bird that Noah let out of the ark?",
    "answer": "A raven",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 737,
    "question": "What was the height of Goliath?",
    "answer": "Six cubits and a span",
    "reference": "1 Sam 17:4"
  },
  {
    "id": 738,
    "question": "What was the judgment seat of Pilate known as?",
    "answer": "The Stone Pavement",
    "reference": "John 19:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 739,
    "question": "What was the name of Aaron’s (Moses’s brother) wife?",
    "answer": "Elisheba",
    "reference": "Exod 6:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 740,
    "question": "What was the name of Abraham’s nephew?",
    "answer": "Lot",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 742,
    "question": "What was the name of David’s father?",
    "answer": "Jesse",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 743,
    "question": "What was the name of Jacob’s daughter?",
    "answer": "Dinah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 746,
    "question": "What was the name of the blind man whom Jesus healed?",
    "answer": "Bartimaeus",
    "reference": "Mark 10:46-52"
  },
  {
    "id": 747,
    "question": "What was the name of the city founded by Cain after he left God's presence?",
    "answer": "Enoch",
    "reference": "Genesis 4:16-17"
  },
  {
    "id": 748,
    "question": "What was the name of the disciple who doubted Jesus' resurrection?",
    "answer": "Thomas",
    "reference": "John 20:24-29"
  },
  {
    "id": 749,
    "question": "What was the name of the garden planted by God for the first couple?",
    "answer": "Garden of Eden",
    "reference": "Genesis 2:8"
  },
  {
    "id": 750,
    "question": "What was the name of the high priest's servant whose ear was cut off by Simon Peter?",
    "answer": "Malchus",
    "reference": "John 18:10"
  },
  {
    "id": 752,
    "question": "What was the name of the man who asked Pilate for Jesus' body?",
    "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea",
    "reference": "John 19:38-42"
  },
  {
    "id": 753,
    "question": "What was the name of the man who climbed a tree to see Jesus?",
    "answer": "Zacchaeus",
    "reference": "Luke 19:1-10"
  },
  {
    "id": 754,
    "question": "What was the name of the member of the Sanhedrin who was a secret disciple of Jesus and who asked Pilate for the body of Jesus?",
    "answer": "Joseph of Arimathaea",
    "reference": "Mark 15:42-45"
  },
  {
    "id": 755,
    "question": "What was the name of the Roman governor who heard Paul?",
    "answer": "Felix",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 756,
    "question": "What was the name of the woman who anointed Jesus' feet?",
    "answer": "Mary",
    "reference": "John 12:1-8"
  },
  {
    "id": 757,
    "question": "What was the name of the woman who hid the spies at Jericho?",
    "answer": "Rahab",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 758,
    "question": "What was the ninth plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 759,
    "question": "What was the other name of Tabitha a woman who was raised from the dead?",
    "answer": "Dorcas",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 763,
    "question": "What was the seventh plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Hail",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 764,
    "question": "What was the tenth plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Death of first-born",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 765,
    "question": "What was the total number of the children of Israel that went down to Egypt?",
    "answer": "70",
    "reference": "Gen 46:27"
  },
  {
    "id": 766,
    "question": "What weapons did Gideon use to defeat the Midianites?",
    "answer": "Trumpets",
    "reference": "pitchers"
  },
  {
    "id": 768,
    "question": "What were men trying to do at the Tower of Babel?",
    "answer": "Built a tower to reach to Heaven",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 769,
    "question": "What were Solomon’s other names?",
    "answer": "Jedediah and Lemuel",
    "reference": "2 Sam 12:25; Prov 31:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 770,
    "question": "What were the “Urim and Thummim”?",
    "answer": "Lots used by the priests",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 773,
    "question": "What’s the first line of the Lord’s Prayer?",
    "answer": "Our Father which art in heaven",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 775,
    "question": "What’s the last word in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "Curse",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 776,
    "question": "What’s the longest book in the Bible?",
    "answer": "The book of Psalms is the longest book in the Old Testament",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 777,
    "question": "What’s the longest chapter in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Psalm 119",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 778,
    "question": "What’s the shortest book in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "The book of Obadiah is the shortest book in the Old Testament",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 780,
    "question": "When God showed Abram the stars in the sky",
    "answer": "what did he promise?",
    "reference": "Abram would have more descendants than the number of stars"
  },
  {
    "id": 781,
    "question": "When Jacob met Laban",
    "answer": "which daughter did he want to marry?",
    "reference": "Rachel"
  },
  {
    "id": 782,
    "question": "When Jesus descended from the mount of transfiguration he was greeted by:",
    "answer": "A man who sought healing for his epileptic son",
    "reference": "Mark 9:1-18"
  },
  {
    "id": 783,
    "question": "When Rachel left home with Jacob her husband what did she steal from her father Laban?",
    "answer": "Laban’s household gods",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 784,
    "question": "When Saul was pursuing David in which cave did David seek refuge?",
    "answer": "Cave of Adullam",
    "reference": "1 Sam 22:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 787,
    "question": "Where did God send Moses to deliver the children of Israel out of Egypt?",
    "answer": "Pharaoh",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 788,
    "question": "Where did Hagar and her son leave to?",
    "answer": "Into the desert",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 791,
    "question": "Where did Mary bring her newborn son Jesus \"\"when the days of her purification according to the law of Moses were accomplished\"\"?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "reference": "Luke 2:22"
  },
  {
    "id": 793,
    "question": "Where did Paul see a vision of Jesus?",
    "answer": "On the road to Damascus",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 795,
    "question": "Where was an altar erected “to the unknown God”?",
    "answer": "Athens",
    "reference": "Acts 17:22–23"
  },
  {
    "id": 797,
    "question": "Where was Jesus crucified?",
    "answer": "Golgotha",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 799,
    "question": "Where was Moses buried?",
    "answer": "In the valley of Moab",
    "reference": "Deut 34:6"
  },
  {
    "id": 800,
    "question": "Where was Paul stoned?",
    "answer": "Lystra",
    "reference": "Acts 14:19"
  },
  {
    "id": 801,
    "question": "Where were the disciples first called “Christians”?",
    "answer": "Antioch",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 802,
    "question": "Which animal spoke to Balaam?",
    "answer": "Donkey",
    "reference": "Numbers 22:28"
  },
  {
    "id": 803,
    "question": "Which apostle led a blind man out of the city to heal him?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 807,
    "question": "Which biblical narrative is connected to Palm Sunday?",
    "answer": "Jesus’ entry into Jerusalem before his death",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 808,
    "question": "Which book comes last in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 810,
    "question": "Which book of the bible begins with „In the beginning was the word“?",
    "answer": "John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 815,
    "question": "Which Gospel is most concerned with the mystery and identity of the person of Jesus?",
    "answer": "John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 816,
    "question": "Which Gospel is written by a doctor?",
    "answer": "Luke",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 817,
    "question": "Which Gospel mostly speaks on the mystery and identity of the person of Jesus?",
    "answer": "The Gospel According to John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 818,
    "question": "Which gospel records the fewest of the miracles performed by Jesus?",
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 819,
    "question": "Which group of people is righteous enough to inherit the Kingdom of God?",
    "answer": "The Gentiles",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 820,
    "question": "Which human author wrote the most books?",
    "answer": "Paul wrote 13 books",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 822,
    "question": "Which insect did John the Baptist eat in the desert?",
    "answer": "Locusts",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 823,
    "question": "Which is the longest and shortest chapter in the Bible?",
    "answer": "The largest is Psalm 119 and the smallest is Psalm 117",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 825,
    "question": "Which literary genre does Jesus implement to help preach his message?",
    "answer": "Parables",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 827,
    "question": "Which New Testament book has Jesus’ Sermon on the Mount?",
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 829,
    "question": "Which of the disciples denied Jesus?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "reference": "Mark 14:66-72"
  },
  {
    "id": 830,
    "question": "Which of the following disciples never saw a vision of the kingdom of God coming with power before they tasted of death?",
    "answer": "Andrew",
    "reference": "Mark 9:1-2"
  },
  {
    "id": 831,
    "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
    "answer": "Moses was the author of the fewest books written in the Bible",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 832,
    "question": "Which of these did not have their name changed in the Bible?",
    "answer": "David",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 833,
    "question": "Which of these disciples of Jesus used to be a disciple of John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Andrew",
    "reference": "John 1:35"
  },
  {
    "id": 834,
    "question": "Which of these miracles did Jesus NOT perform?",
    "answer": "Jesus turned a stone into bread",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 835,
    "question": "Which prophet is known for turning his rod into a bronze snake?",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 836,
    "question": "Which Roman was in charge of cultivation in Syria at the time of Jesus’ birth?",
    "answer": "Quirinus",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 839,
    "question": "Which two books start with \"\"In the beginning\"\"?",
    "answer": "Genesis and John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 840,
    "question": "Which two Old Testament characters appeared with Jesus at the transfiguration?",
    "answer": "Elijah and Moses",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 845,
    "question": "Who asked Jesus if they could be permitted to call down fire from heaven upon the Samaritans?",
    "answer": "James & John",
    "reference": "Luke 9:52-54"
  },
  {
    "id": 846,
    "question": "Who asked Pilate for Jesus’ body after he was crucified?",
    "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 851,
    "question": "Who climbed a mountain at 120 years old and never came back?",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 854,
    "question": "Who did Abraham send to find Isaac a wife?",
    "answer": "His oldest servant",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 857,
    "question": "Who did Isaac favor of his two sons?",
    "answer": "Esau",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 859,
    "question": "Who did Laban trick Jacob into marrying?",
    "answer": "Leah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 860,
    "question": "Who did Moses drown by closing the Red Sea?",
    "answer": "The Egyptians",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 862,
    "question": "Who did the servant choose?",
    "answer": "Rebekah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 867,
    "question": "Who is Abraham’s wife?",
    "answer": "Sarah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 868,
    "question": "Who is Stephen in Acts of the Apostles?",
    "answer": "First Christian martyr",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 869,
    "question": "Who is the author of the Book of Revelation?",
    "answer": "John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 871,
    "question": "Who is the high priest of Jerusalem that put Jesus on trial?",
    "answer": "Caiaphas",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 872,
    "question": "Who is the high priest of Jerusalem who put Jesus on trial?",
    "answer": "Caiaphas",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 876,
    "question": "Who murders John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Herod Antipas",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 877,
    "question": "Who pretended to be mad to avoid capture and death at the hands of an enemy king?",
    "answer": "David",
    "reference": "1 Samuel 21:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 881,
    "question": "Who recognized Jesus as the Messiah when he was presented to the Temple as a baby?",
    "answer": "Simeon",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 882,
    "question": "Who requested for the head of John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Herodias",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 883,
    "question": "Who restored Paul’s sight after the Lord blinded him?",
    "answer": "Ananias",
    "reference": "Acts 9:17–18"
  },
  {
    "id": 884,
    "question": "Who rolled the stone closing Jesus' tomb?",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "reference": "Matthew 27:59-60"
  },
  {
    "id": 887,
    "question": "Who said I say to my servant",
    "answer": "Go",
    "reference": "and he goes?"
  },
  {
    "id": 890,
    "question": "Who said: „Greater love hath no man than this that a man lay down his life for his friends“?",
    "answer": "Jesus",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 893,
    "question": "Who said: „The LORD gave and the LORD hath taken away; blessed be the name of the LORD“?",
    "answer": "Job",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 894,
    "question": "Who suggested that Joseph interpret the dreams of Pharaoh?",
    "answer": "The cupbearer",
    "reference": "Gen 41:12–13"
  },
  {
    "id": 896,
    "question": "Who wanted to kill Jesus when he was a baby?",
    "answer": "Herod",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 900,
    "question": "Who was born first?",
    "answer": "Esau came first with Jacob grabbing his heel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 903,
    "question": "Who was David’s captain?",
    "answer": "Joab",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 904,
    "question": "Who was David’s son that started a rebellion against him?",
    "answer": "Absalom",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 906,
    "question": "Who was Moses’s father-in-law?",
    "answer": "Jethro",
    "reference": "Exod 3:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 907,
    "question": "Who was Solomon’s mother?",
    "answer": "Bathsheba",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 908,
    "question": "Who was the chief of the three mighty men of David?",
    "answer": "Josheb-basshebeth",
    "reference": "2 Sam 23:8"
  },
  {
    "id": 910,
    "question": "Who was the father of John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Zechariah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 912,
    "question": "Who was the first born son of David?",
    "answer": "Amnon",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 913,
    "question": "Who was the first king of Israel?",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 916,
    "question": "Who was the first person to come upon the injured man in the parable of the Good Samaritan?",
    "answer": "Priest",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 920,
    "question": "Who was the grandson of Samuel?",
    "answer": "Heman",
    "reference": "1 Chronicles 6:33"
  },
  {
    "id": 921,
    "question": "Who was the Hebrew judge that Delilah seduced to hand over to the Philistine army?",
    "answer": "Samson",
    "reference": "Judges 16:18-20"
  },
  {
    "id": 922,
    "question": "Who was the high priest during the time of Zechariah?",
    "answer": "Joshua",
    "reference": "Zech 6:10-11"
  },
  {
    "id": 925,
    "question": "Who was the last king of Israel?",
    "answer": "Hoshea",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 927,
    "question": "Who was the most wicked king of Israel?",
    "answer": "Ahab",
    "reference": "1 Kgs 21:25"
  },
  {
    "id": 928,
    "question": "Who was the mother of John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Elizabeth",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 930,
    "question": "Who was the mother of Samuel?",
    "answer": "Hannah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 931,
    "question": "Who was the priest of Bethel during the time of Amos?",
    "answer": "Amaziah",
    "reference": "Amos 7:10"
  },
  {
    "id": 937,
    "question": "Who went with Paul on his first missionary journey?",
    "answer": "Barnabas",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 939,
    "question": "Who were Moses' two siblings?",
    "answer": "Miriam and Aaron",
    "reference": "Exodus 15:20-21 and Exodus 6:16-20"
  },
  {
    "id": 941,
    "question": "Who were the parents of king Josiah?",
    "answer": "Amon and Jedidah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 942,
    "question": "Who worked as a tax collector before preaching the word of God?",
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 943,
    "question": "Who would have nothing to do with the author of 3 John?",
    "answer": "Diotrephes",
    "reference": "3 John 1:9"
  },
  {
    "id": 944,
    "question": "Who wrote most of the books in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 945,
    "question": "Who wrote the Acts of the Apostles?",
    "answer": "Luke",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 946,
    "question": "Who wrote the Book of Revelation?",
    "answer": "John",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 948,
    "question": "Whose example does Paul say Christians should follow in Chapter 5 of Ephesians?",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 950,
    "question": "Why did God send the ten plagues?",
    "answer": "Pharaoh refused to let the Israelites free",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1469,
    "question": "According to Paul’s formulation in 1 Corinthians, which is the greatest of the imperishable qualities?",
    "answer": "Love",
    "reference": "1 Corinthians 13:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 1471,
    "question": "According to the Gospel of Matthew, where does Jesus give his first public sermon?",
    "answer": "On the mount",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1472,
    "question": "According to the Gospel of Matthew, where does Jesus’s first public sermon take place?",
    "answer": "Mount",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1481,
    "question": "As Isaac was dying and blind, who suggested that Jacob should steal the blessing?",
    "answer": "Rebekah",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1559,
    "question": "In the Gospel of Mark, how does the Virgin Mary learn of her pregnancy",
    "answer": "From the angel Gabriel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1581,
    "question": "Paul and Silas were imprisoned during the second missionary journey, but in what city did this happen?",
    "answer": "Philippi",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1585,
    "question": "Prior to raising Eutychus from the dead, Paul preached a lengthy sermon At what hour did he end his sermon?",
    "answer": "Midnight",
    "reference": "Acts 20:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 1608,
    "question": "What did Jesus do before feeding the 5,000",
    "answer": "Gave thanks",
    "reference": "John 6:11"
  },
  {
    "id": 1746,
    "question": "When Jacob met Laban, which daughter did he want to marry?",
    "answer": "Rachel",
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1852,
    "question": "Who said I say to my servant, Go, and he goes?",
    "answer": "A Centurion",
    "reference": "Matthew 8:8"
  }
]